## natali vlatko

dolziger straße 28 • 10247 berlin, germany • **CELL** (+49) 152 2777 8666 • **E-MAIL** natalivlatko@gmail.com •

## **PROFILE**

Writing, branding, communications, strategy. Strong background in research and analysis, with close attention to detail. Well organised, efficient, and can operate effectively when working individually or within a team. Experience in companies with a global reach, spanning several countries (Australia, Singapore, Germany).

Proficient in various open source versions of proprietary software including CMS, chat clients, office suites, and browsers.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Head of Tech Communications (Wayfair) BERLIN, GERMANY - NOV 2017 - PRESENT

- Help develop and coordinate a tech communications strategy and additional services to grow Wayfair's global technology brand, showcasing its technical prowess and initiatives.
- Create and contribute to strategic communication plans that drive broader visibility via various social media and blogging channels, plus internal channels.
- Prepare communications materials in partnership with Public Relations for tech media and stakeholders including articles, presentations, speeches, and other digital support materials.
- Close monitoring, documenting, and reporting of social media and blog activity, including analytical statistics and data.
- Review speaking and event sponsorship opportunities for the Engineering department globally.
- Create and facilitate tech meetups, events, and conferences for local markets and abroad.
- Write and edit opinion pieces, thought leadership articles, and internal communications on behalf of Wayfair's Engineering leadership.
- Curate and coordinate Wayfair's Open Source Software strategy, whilst working with Engineering teams to produce accurate documentation for projects and craft marketing plans for their release.
- Work with Tech Talent Development teams to plan, organize, and execute hackathons for the wider Engineering population at Wayfair, extending it's scope for Data Science and Product groups.
- Creation and maintenance of tech resources such as Wayfair's Tech Radar, Tech Blog, and newsletter content, working closely with Talent Acquisition for utilisation in recruiting.

Corporate Communications Manager - Tech, Zalando SE BERLIN, GERMANY - MAR 2016 - OCT 2017

Journalist/Editor, Software & Support Media (JAXenter.com) BERLIN, GERMANY - JAN 2015 - JAN 2016

Admissions/Student Services Manager, Nexus International School SINGAPORE, SINGAPORE - 2013 - MAY 2014

Customer Service Manager, APACSALE Group SINGAPORE, SINGAPORE - 2013

Client Services Manager, State Library of New South Wales SYDNEY, AUSTRALIA - 2011 - JAN 2013

## **EDUCATION**

Master of Arts, Ancient History University of Macquarie, NSW - 2012

Bachelor of Arts, History, Politics, Philosophy University of Western Sydney, NSW - 2009